YEONSU PARK

८ +82 10-9688-7293 **♥** Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

≥ yeonsu.park@kangwon.ac.kr in linkedin.com/in/yeonsu-park ↑ park-yeonsu.github.io

SUMMARY

I am an assistant professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at Kangwon National University. Previously, I was a postdoctoral research scientist at POSTECH. I received my Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering from POSTECH, where I was fortunate to be advised by Professor Wook-Shin Han. Before that, I obtained my B.S. degree in Software Engineering from Sungkyunkwan University. My research interests include big data processing, query processing, and query optimization.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering, POSTECH	Feb. 2018 - Feb. 2024
--	-----------------------

Advisor: Prof. Wook-Shin Han

B.S. in Software Engineering, Sungkyunkwan University

Mar. 2011 - Feb. 2017

Graduated with 1st rank in Dept. of Software GPA: 4.35/4.5 (Major-only GPA: 4.43/4.5)

Took leave of absence for two years (for mandatory military service)

EMPLOYMENT

Assistant Professor, Kangwon National University, Republic of Korea	Sep. 2024 - Present
Postdoctoral Research Scientist, POSTECH, Republic of Korea	Feb. 2024 - Aug. 2024
Researcher, POSTECH, Republic of Korea	Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2018
Software Engineer Intern, NCSOFT, Republic of Korea	Jan. 2012 - Feb. 2012

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Big Data Processing, Database Query Processing and Optimization, Algorithms

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-reviewed Conference Papers

- [1] QaaD (Query-as-a-Data): Scalable Execution of Massive Number of Small Queries in Spark Yeonsu Park, Byungchul Tak, and Wook-Shin Han ACM SIGMOD 2023 (Top Database Conference)
- [2] A Study on the Construction of a Database for On-site Safety Accidents in Hazardous Chemical Workplaces Jaehyun Ha, Sangoh Lee, Taesung Lee, <u>Yeonsu Park</u>, and Wook-Shin Han KDBC 2023
- [3] G-CARE: A Framework for Performance Benchmarking of Cardinality Estimation Techniques for Subgraph Matching
 - <u>Yeonsu Park</u>, Seongyun Ko, Sourav S. Bhowmick, Kyoungmin Kim, Kijae Hong, and Wook-Shin Han **ACM SIGMOD 2020** (Top Database Conference)
- [4] A Survey on Worst-case Optimal Join Algorithms <u>Yeonsu Park</u>, Taesung Lee, Seung-Min Lee, Junseung Hwang, and Wook-Shin Han Korean Information Science Society Conference, 2018
- [5] A Survey of Methods for Dynamic Graph Updates on the State-of-the-art Graph Processing Systems Seung-Min Lee, Jeong-Hwan Kim, Byeonghoon So, <u>Yeonsu Park</u>, and Wook-Shin Han Korean Information Science Society Conference, 2018

[6] Performance Evaluation of RocksDB Depending on Sync Option Yeonsu Park, Gihwan Oh, Jong-baek Lee, Woon-Hak Kang, and Sang-Won Lee Korean Information Science Society Conference, 2014

Dissertation

 [7] Scalable Execution of Massive Number of Small Queries in Spark <u>Yeonsu Park</u>
 Ph.D. Dissertation, 2024

Patents

[8] DISTRIBUTED PROCESSING SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR PROCESSING DATA Wook-Shin Han, <u>Yeonsu Park</u>, and Kijae Hong KR Patent No. 10-2022-0110236, 2022

[9] ELECTRONIC APPARATUS AND DATA PROCESSING METHOD THEREOF, AND SYSTEM FOR DISTRIBUTED PROCESSING

Young Hwa Lee, Wook-Shin Han, Hyeonji Kim, and <u>Yeonsu Park</u> KR Patent No. 10-2021-0172678, 2021

AWARDS AND HONORS

Google Conference Scholarship Samsung Humantech Paper Award (Computer Science & Engineering) - Silver Prize	2023 2020
Graduation with 1st rank in Dept. of Software, Sungkyunkwan University	2017
ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ACM-ICPC) World Finals	
- Special Award	
- 45th Place	
ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ACM-ICPC) Asia Regional (Korea Site)	2013
- 4th Place	
ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ACM-ICPC) World Finals	2013
- 48th Place	
ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ACM-ICPC) Asia Regional (Korea Site)	2012
- 2nd Place	
Sungkyun Software Scholarship 2011	- 2016
Dean's List, College of Computing, Sungkyunkwan University 2011	- 2016
- Recognized on the Dean's List for seven semesters	
Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI)	2009
- Silver Medal	

PROJECTS

Scalable Execution of Massive Number of Small Queries in Spark

2022 - 2023

Ph.D. Student, POSTECH

Pohang, Republic of Korea

- Achieved substantial performance improvement in Spark for small query workloads by proposing and implementing a query merge-based technique, resulting in 10.6× to 36.6× faster processing compared to standard Spark executions.
- Published at SIGMOD 2023.

Scalable Sequential Pattern Mining in Spark

2020 - 2022

Ph.D. Student, POSTECH (collaborated with Samsung Electronics)

Pohang, Republic of Korea

• Parallelized the cSPADE algorithm in Spark, achieving a 100× improvement in scalability compared to the sequential pattern mining algorithm of Spark MLlib.

Performance Benchmarking of Cardinality Estimation Techniques for Subgraph Matching 2018 - 2020 Ph.D. Student, POSTECH Pohang, Republic of Korea

- Proposed and developed a comprehensive framework for cardinality estimation techniques, enabling the realization of existing methods and providing insights on their performance, by identifying serious accuracy issues in various scenarios and datasets.
- Discovered that a simple method designed for relational data consistently outperforms all others on graph data.
- Published at SIGMOD 2020.

ACADEMIC TALKS

QaaD (Query-as-a-Data): Scalable Execution of Massive Number of Small Queries in Spark

• ACM SIGMOD 2023, Seattle, WA, USA

Jun. 2023

G-CARE: A Framework for Performance Benchmarking of Cardinality Estimation Techniques for Subgraph Matching

• Top Conference Session, Korea Computer Congress 2020 (Virtual)

Jul. 2020

• ACM SIGMOD 2020, Portland, OR, USA (Virtual)

Jun. 2020

• SAP Labs Korea, Seoul, Republic of Korea

Nov. 2019

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer

SIGMOD Record (2024)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Instructor	Kangwon National University – 4471030 Database	Fall 2024
	Kangwon National University – 4471016 Algorithms	Fall 2024
	Kangwon National University – 1410033 C Programming	Fall 2024
Teaching Assistant	POSTECH – CSED421 Database System	Spring 2021
	Samsung – Advanced Data Programming	2020
	POSTECH – CSED421 Database System	Fall 2020
	POSTECH – CSED421 Database System	Fall 2019

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C/C++, Python, Scala, Bash

Software & Technologies

Big Data Framework (Apache Spark), Databases

REFERENCES

Wook-Shin Han, Professor, POSTECH

Byungchul Tak, Associate Professor, Kyungpook National University

✓ wshan@dblab.postech.ac.kr

➤ bctak@knu.ac.kr